#### LEAD GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Professional with 14 years of invaluable hands-on experience managing multiple concurrent creative design projects, concept creation, and graphic design. In order to maximize productivity and ensure customer satisfaction, excel at overcoming design difficulties with new ideas and process improvements.





+91 97 8986 8586



mdoovaisechn1987@gmail.com



www.behance.net/mdoovaise

#### PERSONAL INFO

DATE OF BIRTH 7.5.1987 NATIONALITY INDIA MARITAL STATUS MARRIED

LANGUAGES KNOWN **ENGLISH, TAMIL** 

**ADDRESS** 237, ALAGENDRAN PLAZA, VALLUVAR COLONY,

VASUKI NAGAR 3RD STREET, MADURAI

#### **PROFILE**

I have 14 years of industry expertise as a Creative visualization specialist and have worked on several excellent firms' graphic design, branding, and typography projects during that time. I have an optimistic attitude toward life and am working hard to reach my goals. Il began to develop my abilities after becoming interested in arts and design during my school years. By the time I finished my Multimedia Diploma. I aspire to be a top-rated Art Director by understanding these technologies.

## **EDUCATION**

**B.Sc. - MATHEMATICS** UNIVERSITY OF MADRAS CHENNAI, TN, INDIA

**DIPLOMA IN MULTIMEDIA** THE IMAGE CHENNAI, TN, INDIA

## TECHNICAL SKILLS





















## **GENERAL SKILLS**

LEADERSHIP TIME MANAGEMENT FFICIENCY TEAM WORK

MULTI-TASKING DECISION MAKING EMERGENCY PLANNING & RESPONSE

LEAD GRAPHIC DESIGNER

+91 97 8986 8586 M mdoovaisechn1987@gmail.com



www.behance.net/mdoovaise

#### **ROLES & RESPONSIBILITES**

- Conceptualize and create visually stunning designs for a variety of marketing collateral, including digital campaigns, social media graphics, and website visuals.
- Develop illustrations, logos and other designs using software or by hand
- Development of highly creative, engaging and original ideas/assets that reinforce brand position and provide clear commercial communication
- Work with the wider marketing team to create innovative marketing campaigns and manage the creative direction, design templates, and production
- Co ordinated with the printing vendors to get the design requirements on time
- Manage all production of all white label assets for agent partners, including magazines, videos, and sales collateral
- Take on the role of 'brand guardian' ensuring all external/internal assets and touchpoints are in line with brand guideline
- Transform complex concepts into visually engaging infographics, illustrations, and presentations
- Stay up-to-date with design trends, industry best practices, and emerging technologies to deliver cutting-edge visual solutions
- Manage multiple projects simultaneously, adhering to strict deadlines while maintaining exceptional attention to detail
- Continuously evolve and refine design processes, seeking opportunities for innovation and efficiency

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Successfully handled 4 designing projects simultaneously, delivering all of them within the deadline
- Singlehandedly incorporated changes into a design, which was made by another graphic designer
- Oversaw the work of an entire design team of 5 individuals
- Trained newly hired graphic designers in working with Adobe Creative Suite
- Consistently met deadlines for all creative work between the years 2019 and 2023
- Coordinated efforts of artists, web designers, printers, and marketers. Received high commendations for exceptional efforts in a marketing campaign
- Picked from a designer pool of 50 to solely work on a large multinational marketing and promotional campaign for US magazine

LEAD GRAPHIC DESIGNER

+91 97 8986 8586 M mdoovaisechn1987@gmail.com



www.behance.net/mdoovaise

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### ARS STEELS & ALLOY INTERNATIONAL PVT. LTD.

NOV 2019 - JUNE 2023

#### CREATIVE DESIGNER - LEAD

- Manage a Team of Design Experts
- Allocating daily jobs and work loads
- Monitoring the team performance
- Creating motion-graphic videos and video editing for inhouse needs
- Developed design deliverables that elevated, differentiated and functioned on-brand and on-strategy
- Translated complex concepts and data into compelling visuals for media outreach
- Designed new on-brand visual elements to effectively convey concepts and messaging
- Formatted text and graphics for blog posts, newsletters and other materials
- Collaborated with internal clients to determine strategy and design for annual marketing campaigns
- Generated new ideas with limited direction and varied internal client needs
- Edited existing Powerpoint slides to enhance the corporate message
- Generated detailed specs of final designs
- Designed advertisements, trade show banners and signage from concept through completion
- Designed print and marketing initiatives for all website properties

#### HCL TECHNOLOGIES LIMITED

SEP 2014 - SEP 2019

#### SENIOR GRAPHIC DEISGNER

- Attend client meetings and understand their brand and promotion requirements
- Come up with innovative concepts and get approval from the clients
- Carry out detailed research and create design briefs for approval
- Estimate the time required to complete the designs and send quotes accordingly
- Send out the completed designs to the clients for feedback
- Overseeing of working with luxury brands
- Solving design problems where no answer is apparent
- Juggling multiple projects while effectively managing timeliness and expectations
- Keeping up to date with current design technology
- Thinking creatively to produce new ideas and concepts
- Ability to work under pressure, priorities schedules and manage workloads

LEAD GRAPHIC DESIGNER

+91 97 8986 8586 M mdoovaisechn1987@gmail.com



www.behance.net/mdoovaise

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TWG APPLIED SERVICES (I) PVT. LTD.

JAN 2014 - SEP 2014

#### SENIOR GRAPHIC DEISGNER

- Designing Ads for HAYMARKET Newspaper
- Coordinating with the onsite designers and designing ads for motor sports, real estates
- Design ads based on the themes and specs
- Image color correction and retouching
- Meet client requirements within the specified turn around time
- Providing concepts and preparing mocks for magazine feature pages and cover
- Key player in creative and template projects
- Design magazines and product catalogs

#### **HCL TECHNOLOGIES LIMITED**

OCT 2010 - JAN 2014

## **GRAPHIC DEISGNER**

- Coordinating with the Editors and design magazines for motor sports, fashion and healthcare industry
- Design Ads based on Themes and Specs
- Meet editor's requirements within the specified turnaround time
- Providing concepts and preparing mocks for feature pages and cover
- Key player in creative and template projects
- Design magazines and product catalogs
- Create specific style guides and documents for magazines
- Creating Covers and special Show guides
- Doing Creative workshops with onshore designers

#### **INTERESTS**

CRICKET

TRAVELING

SOCIAL ACTIVITY

**WEBINARS** 

HORTICULTURE EXERCISING & HEALTHCARE

VOLUNTEERISM